getuseful.com 2016-10-23

# 

Useful Systems, Inc.
Privacy Policy
Last Modified October __, 2015
This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) discloses the privacy practices of Useful Systems, Inc. (“Useful”) and the
possible uses of the information that Useful gathers via www.usefulsystemsinc.com and any related
web sites (collectively, the "Site”) along with software applications for mobile and desktop platforms (the
“Applications”). The Site and the Applications, together with any other products and services provided by
Useful, are collectively referred to as the Service (the “Service”).
Except as set forth in any other Useful agreement or terms and conditions, this Policy does not apply to
information collected by Useful offline or through any other means, including on any other website
operated by Company or any third party, or through any third party, including through any applications or
content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Service.
Please read this Policy carefully to understand Useful’s policies and practices regarding your information
and how Useful will treat it. If you do not agree with this Policy, including having your personally
identifiable information ("Personal Information" as defined below) used in any of the ways described in this
Privacy Policy, your choice is not to use the Service or you may be precluded from using much of the
Service and your account with Useful may be terminated and suspended. By accessing or using the
Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy.
You should also read Useful’s Website Terms of Use located at www.usefulsystemsinc.com/TermsOfUse
(the “Terms of Use”). Capitalized terms that are used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the same
meaning and description as stated in the Terms of Use.
Information Collected
Useful collects information on its users in various ways, such as by voluntary submissions, participation
in services provided via the Site and the Applications, from third parties, and through cookie and other
tracking technology. Useful collects the following information:
      • Personal Information. "Personal Information" refers to information that tells Useful specifically
   who you are, such as your name, phone number, email address, postal address, and possibly
   information relating to certain support or customer service issues. Much of this Personal Information
   is collected when you create an Account using the Service.
      • Financial Information. Useful may also collect and store credit card, bank account or other
   payment information in order to periodically charge you for the use of any paid components of the
   Service.
       • Submission of User Content. Useful collects User Content such as messages, posts, comments,
  and responses that you voluntarily provide in Useful’s Support & Community Areas or through the
  Applications. Certain Support & Community Areas are deemed public, and Useful may in its sole
  discretion share any User Content submitted in these areas with others. Other Support & Community
  Areas are private, and any User Content submitted in these areas will only be accessible to the User’s

  employer and its employees.
    •   Aggregate Information. Useful may collect general, non-personal, statistical information about the
    use of the Site, Applications and Service, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on the Site,
    how long they stay on that page, and which hyperlinks, if any, they click on. This information
    represents a generic overview of our users, including their collective viewing habits, and allows us and
    other third parties to modify information, promotions, offers and/or discounts on products and
    services based on user traffic and behavior. Useful collects this information through the use of
    technologies such as 'cookies' and web beacons, which are discussed in greater detail below. Useful
    collects this information in order to help enhance the Site and Service.
    •   Usage Details. When you access and use the Applications, Useful may automatically collect
    certain details of your access to and use of the Applications, including traffic data, location data, logs
    and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on or through the
    Applications.
    •   Device Information. Useful may collect information about your mobile device and internet
    connection, including the device's unique device identifier, IP address, operating system, browser type,
    mobile network information and the device's telephone number.
    •   Stored Information and Files. The Applications also may access metadata and other information
    associated with other files stored on your device. This may include, for example, photographs, audio
    and video clips, personal contacts and address book information.
    •   Location Information. This Applications collect real-time information about the location of your
    device.
Third Party Information
Useful may supplement information you provide to Useful with information from other sources, such as
information to validate or update your address, payment card or other demographic and lifestyle
information. Useful use this information to help it maintain the accuracy of the information it collects, to
enable Useful to provide the Service, to target its communications so that Useful can inform you of
products, services and offers that may be of interest, and for internal business analysis or other
business purposes consistent with the Service.
Cookies
Useful may automatically collect non-personally identifiable information and data through the use of
cookies. Cookies are small text files a website uses to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user's
ongoing access to the website and facilitate the use of the website. Cookies also allow a website to
track usage behavior and compile site usage information that will allow for the improvement of content
and target advertising. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept
them and how to remove them. You may set your browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you
may choose to block cookies with your browser. However, please be aware that some features of the
Service may not function or may be slower if you refuse cookies. You may also get cookies from our
advertisers or other third parties with links on the Site as described below. We do not control these
cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third party ad servers is standard in the Internet industry.
Other Tracking Technologies
Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet
protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates
and times that the Site, Applications and Services are accessed. An IP address is a number that is
automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web. Web servers, the computers

that 'serve up' webpages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. The Site, Applications
and Services may also use technology called "tracer tags". These may also be referred to as "Pixels",
"Clear GIFs" or "Web Beacons". This technology allows Useful to understand which pages you visit on the
Site and other ways you interact with the Site and the Service. These tracer tags are used to help Useful
to optimize and tailor the Site and Services for you and other users of our Site and the Service. Useful
may link the information it records using tracking technologies to Personal Information Useful collects.
Use of Information
The information Useful collects is used in a variety of ways, including:
    •    For internal review
    •    To provide and improve the Site, Applications and the Service, and to deliver a better and more
         personalized experience by enabling Useful to
              o   Estimate the audience size and usage patterns
              o   Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize the Service according
                  to your individual interests
              o   Speed up your searches
              o   Recognize you when you use the Service
    •    To optimize third-party offers of products and/or services
    •    To verify the legitimacy of User Content
    •    To notify you about updates to the Site, Applications and the Service
    •    To let you know about products, services, and promotions that you may be interested in
    •    For marketing purposes and the marketing of discounts offered through the Site, Applications
         and the Service by service contractors ("Service Providers")
    •    Internal business analysis or other business purposes consistent with our mission
Disclosures and Transfers of Information
Useful does not disclose Personal Information to third parties, except when one or more of the following
conditions is true:
    •    Useful has your permission to make the disclosure
    •    The disclosure is consistent with the purpose for which the Personal Information was obtained
    •    The disclosure is to financial service providers in order to fulfill and carry out the purchase and
         provision of the Service requested by you
    •    The Personal Information to be disclosed is publicly available
    •    The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or other disposition of all or part of Useful’s
         business or assets
    •    The disclosure is for Useful’s own marketing purposes, or, with your authorization, for the
         marketing purposes of third parties
    •    The party to whom the disclosure is made controls, is controlled by, or is under common control
         with Useful
    •    The disclosure is in Useful’s sole discretion necessary for the establishment or maintenance of
         legal claims or legal compliance, to satisfy any law, regulation, subpoena or government request,
         or in connection with litigation
    •    The disclosure is in Useful’s sole discretion about users who Useful believes are engaged in illegal
         activities or are otherwise in violation of the Terms of Use or other agreement with Useful, even
         without a subpoena, warrant or court order
    •    The disclosure is to outside businesses to perform certain services for Useful, such as
         maintaining the Site, Applications and the Service, mailing lists, processing orders and delivering

         products and services, sending postal mail, providing marketing assistance, and data analysis
         ("Administrative Service Providers")
Prior to sharing of your Personal Information with others, agreements are made between Useful and such
outside parties to whom Useful is transferring data. If Useful becomes aware that any such outside party
is improperly using or disclosing Personal Information, it will notify that outside party and request that it
take reasonable steps to cease such use or disclosure.
Useful may also disclose aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of the Site, Applications and
Services to Useful’s existing or potential business partners or other third parties, or in response to a
government request. Useful may also share aggregated demographic and preference data with third
parties to enable the provision of targeted information, promotions, offers and/or discounts on products
and services.
Choice: Opt-in/Opt-out
To help you review, edit, and control how we use much of the information Useful collects about you, you
can visit your account webpage on the Site or through the Application, where you can update certain
information and unsubscribe from receiving specific types of email messages and telephone calls. You
cannot, however, unsubscribe from receiving certain emails, such as account status and billing related
emails.
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being
sent. You can also choose whether or not to allow the Application to collect information through other
tracking technologies on the device. If you disable or refuse cookies or block the use of other tracking
technologies, some parts of the Service may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
For location information, you can choose whether or not to allow the Application to collect and use real-
time information about your device's location through the device's privacy settings. If you block the use of
location information, some parts of the Service may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
If you delete your User Contributions from the Service, copies of your User Contributions may remain
viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other users. Proper access
and use of information provided on the Service, including User Contributions, is governed by the Website
Terms of Use or the Applications’ end user license agreement.
Useful may provide certain Personal Information as a service to others for their marketing purposes. If
you properly notify Useful that you no longer want Useful to share your Personal Information with such
third parties, Useful will cease sharing your Personal Information. However, except as otherwise stated in
this Privacy Policy, Useful does not control the third parties to which Useful shares such Personal
Information and you will need to further notify such third parties directly if you would like them to cease
use of your Personal Information. You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network
Advertising Initiative ("NAI") on the NAI's website.
Data Security, Integrity, and Access
The Personal Information you provide and Useful collects is stored within databases that Useful controls
directly or through its Administrative Service Providers. As Useful deems appropriate, Useful use’s
security measures consistent with industry standards, such as firewalls, to protect your Personal
Information. Useful also uses industry standard encryption technology to protect credit card and
password information. However, since no security system is impenetrable, Useful cannot guarantee the
security of the databases, nor can it guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while
being transmitted over the Internet.
Your information may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state,

province, or country where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those where you live. If you are
located outside the United States and choose to provide information to Useful, please be aware that
Useful transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes and store it there. By submitting
your Personal Information, you consent to having your personal data transferred to, processed, and stored
in the United States.
Any user ID and password associated with your account may only be used by you. You may not share your
user ID and password with anyone else, and you are solely responsible for maintaining and protecting the
confidentiality of your user ID and password. You are fully responsible for all activities that occur under
your user ID and password. You can access and update your login information on your account webpage.
Third Party Websites and Links
Please note that you may have cookies placed on your computer by third party websites that refer you to
the Site. Although we do not share your Personal Information with these third party websites unless you
have authorized us to do so, they may be able to link certain non-personally identifiable information Useful
transfers to them with Personal Information they previously collected from you.
The Site, Applications and the Service may contain links (including advertising banners) to other sites
operated by third parties. Please review the privacy policies of each website you visit to better understand
their privacy practices. Useful does not control such other sites and is not responsible for their content,
their privacy policies, or their use of Personal Information. Useful's inclusion of such links does not, by
itself, imply any endorsement of the content on such sites or of their owners or operators except as
disclosed on the Site and Services. Any information submitted by you directly to these third parties is
subject to that third party's privacy policy. While we support the protection of our customer's privacy on
the Internet, Useful expressly disclaims any and all liability for the actions of third parties, including but
without limitation to actions relating to the use and/or disclosure of Personal Information by third parties.
Children's Privacy
Useful does not intend the Site and the Service to be used by individuals under the age of 18 without the
supervision of a parent or guardian 18 years of age or older. Useful relies upon parents or guardians 18
years of age or older to determine if the Site and the Service is appropriate for the viewing, access, or
participation by such individuals under the age of 18. If an individual under the age of 18 uses the Site
and the Service, such individual may only use the Site and the Service under the supervision of a parent or
guardian 18 years of age or older.
Useful does not seek or knowingly collect any Personal Information about children under 13 years of age.
If Useful becomes aware that it unknowingly collected Personal Information from a child under the age of
13, Useful will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.
Governing Law; Visitors Residing Outside the United States
This Privacy Policy and the privacy practices of Useful will be subject exclusively to the laws of Colorado,
without regard to its conflict of law principles, and the applicable laws of the United States. Useful makes
no representation that this Privacy Policy and such practices comply with the laws of any country outside
the United States.
Changes to Privacy Policy
Useful may update this Privacy Policy from time-to-time in its sole discretion. It is your responsibility to
review the Privacy Policy for any changes each time that you use the Site and Services and you are bound
by such changes. Use of the Site and Services by you following us posting a new privacy policy on our
Site constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Policy as modified.

Your California Privacy Rights
California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of the Service and Site that are California residents
to request certain information regarding Useful’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for
their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to or write us at the
addresses identified below.
How To Contact Us
All requests, questions or concerns about your Personal Information or this Privacy Policy, please contact
us by mail or email at the following:
1007 Pearl Street Suite 200
Boulder CO 80302
Attn: Legal
E-mail: info@usefulsystemsinc.com
Useful welcomes your questions and comments.
